<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on ElixirFocus</title>
    <link>https://elixirfocus.com/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on ElixirFocus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://elixirfocus.com/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir Terminology: Parameters vs Attributes</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/parameters-vs-attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/parameters-vs-attributes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about being explicit and mindful about programming terminology before and today we&amp;rsquo;ll look at another specific Elixir terminology example: parameters vs attributes.
If you create a new Phoenix app and use the generators to stub out a simple CRUD experience you will no doubt observe web controller functions like:
defmodule HelloWeb.PostController do # ... def create(conn, %{&amp;#34;post&amp;#34; =&amp;gt; post_params}) do case Blog.create_post(post_params) do # ... end end end And internal schema module functions like:</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Schemaless Changesets to Separate Concerns Between the Web Context and the Business Context</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/ecto-schemaless-changesets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/ecto-schemaless-changesets/</guid>
      <description>With schemaless changesets you have the power to hand craft validations for specific web form presentations and define firm boundaries of responsibilities between your web presentation layer and the business-specific contexts of your app.
 It&amp;rsquo;s a story we can all relate with. A new app is born using mix phx.new hello.
Some mix phx.gen generators are used to begin to shape a solution, perhaps something like:
$ mix phx.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retro Taxi: September 2021 Update</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/retro-taxi-project-sept-2021-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 09:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/retro-taxi-project-sept-2021-update/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I kicked off the next sample project for this website, a team retrospective board built using Phoenix LiveView called RetroTaxi. More info about the project is available in the project kickoff and today I&amp;rsquo;ll share how it has been coming along.
  From the scope of the original pitch document you&amp;rsquo;d like to think I would have gotten further along by now but a mix of client responsibilities and then a extended personal vacation kept me distracted.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources and Suggestions to Find Elixir-based Employment</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/elixir-job-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 16:12:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/elixir-job-resources/</guid>
      <description>The following is a collection of resources and suggestions for people looking to acquire full time or project specific employment writing Elixir. I personally lean more on consulting but the topic of Elixir employment comes up enough that I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share what I&amp;rsquo;m aware of.
Elixir Job Listings First we have the aptly named elixirjobs.net, which provides an active catalog of known job listings.
I also highly recommend the #jobs, #jobs_chat, and #looking_for_contract rooms of the official Elixir Slack</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve the Clarity of Your Elixir Code Through Expressive and Consistent Language</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/programming-terminology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/programming-terminology/</guid>
      <description>One of our primary day-to-day responsibilities as programmers is to communicate. We need to express our ideas, explain our work and document our code. Having a strong vocabulary and explicit intentions behind the words you (and your team) choose can greatly help avoid confusion.
Take some time as a team to talk about how you name and describe things. Embrace productive confrontation when you identify inconsistencies and work towards creating (and documenting!</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding when to use String-based Maps vs Atom-based Maps</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/string-vs-atom-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:56:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/string-vs-atom-maps/</guid>
      <description>While browsing the ElixirForum the other day I spotted this question from Dominic which resonated deeply with my own experiences learning Elixir. Dominic asks:
 I&amp;rsquo;m constantly being blocked by maps&#39; different construct %{:atom =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;value&amp;quot;} vs. %{&amp;quot;string&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;value&amp;quot;} vs %{name: &amp;quot;value&amp;quot;}.
It does not appears to be consistent enough and in my case are often the cause of all &amp;ldquo;blockage&amp;rdquo; I have.
I understand them, I&amp;rsquo;m a long time Elm dev/fan and used to FP, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know why Elixir&amp;rsquo;s maps are so weird to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RetroTaxi Project Kickoff</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/retro-taxi-project-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 16:55:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/retro-taxi-project-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>Phoenix by Example is all about crafting educational content extracted from open source example projects. Today I am kicking off my latest example project, RetroTaxi!
From the pitch document:
 A retrospective meeting is a regular practice of agile teams or any group of people who are looking for continued improvement to their team process, communication or habits. Successful retro meetings give the team an opportunity to reflect on what is working, what is not and what they want to do next.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Webhook Payload Delivery in Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/securing-webhook-payload-delivery-in-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/securing-webhook-payload-delivery-in-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Some of the most interesting and valuable behaviors we can build as web developers are through connecting different web applications together. Often times this comes in the form of webhooks, where one web app will POST events to your own web app. Keeping that communication secure is important and today we will take a peak into how you can secure webhook payloads in a Phoenix application.
Webhook Security 101 Webhook might sound like some scary, exotic term but at the end of the day webhooks are nothing more that a web server endpoint configured to receive HTTP POST requests in some agreed upon format.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Tradeoffs with Elixir Typespecs and Dialyzer</title>
      <link>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/typespecs-and-dialyzer-tradeoffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 08:51:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elixirfocus.com/posts/typespecs-and-dialyzer-tradeoffs/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s post I want to start a conversation around the tradeoffs of using Typespecs and Dialyzer use in your Elixir code.
Elixir is a dynamic, not a statically-typed language &amp;ndash; and just to preemptively avoid the programming wars that might ensue, the given type system of a language is not a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; attribute by itself, but it will none-the-less influences the code we write.
For those who prefer or come to Elixir from a statically-typed language background you may be interested in learning more about Elixir Typespecs, described in the documentation as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
